Guide to the Washington D.C. published material about education and community life collection, 1965-2003 MS2206
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington D.C. published material about education and community life
1965-2003
1989-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington Institute of Public Policy
MS2206
2.25 Linear Feet
This collection contains published reports, essays, promotional material, audits, surveys, directories, development proposals, and other published material. The material dates from 1965 to 2003, but the bulk of the material dates from 1989 to 1996. These are materials created by and/or collected at the George Washington Institute of Public Policy. The majority of the collection deals with DC public schools.
Arrangement note
Arranged alphabetically by file title
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Transferred by George Washington Institute of Public Policy, 8/24/2006 (2007.004)
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains published reports, essays, promotional material, audits, institutional policies, articles, surveys, directories, annual reports, development proposals, clippings, and some unpublished notes and essays. The material dates from 1965 to 2003, but the bulk of the material dates from 1989 to 1996. These are materials created by and/or collected at the George Washington Institute of Public Policy. The majority of the collection deals with DC public schools, but other material relates to DC demographics, government, development, housing, community resources, and community life. Some of the material was written by professors at GW, including six reports by George Grier.
Historical note
The George Washington Institute of Public Policy (GWIPP) serves as a university-wide center for faculty and graduate students engaging in research on important public policy issues. GWIPP is a stand-alone unit reporting directly to the Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs through the Associate Vice President for Research and Graduate Studies. The Center for Washington Area Studies (CWAS) and the State and Local Fiscal Policy Research Program (SLFP) are housed within GWIPP.
As Director of the Center for Washington Area Studies, Jeffrey R. Henig (1951- ) was instrumental in the gathering of these documents for inclusion in this collection. Henig is now a Professor of Political Science & Education at Teachers College and Professor of Political Science at Columbia University.
Education, Higher -- United States; Education -- United States -- History; Education; Public schools Washington (D.C.); Washington (D.C.) Politics and government; George Washington Institute of Public Policy
- Alliance for Schools that Work, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Analysis of DC Population Change, 05/1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Audit of DC Public Schools, 04/15/1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Balancing the Districts Budgets, 03/1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bringing Educational Services to Students, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Changing Population of DC, 05/1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Children in Crisis: Statistics, Facts, and Figures, 11/1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Coming and Going in the DC Area, 04/1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Community Small Business Survey, 04/1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, 05/1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Council of Governments reports, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Council of the District of Columbia Owners Manuals, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Curriculum Audit of DC Public Schools, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- DC Comprehensive Annual Financial Report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- DC Data, 12/1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- DC Goals 2000, 07/09/1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- DC Public Schools Annual Report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- DC Public Schools Directory, 11/1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- DC Public Schools Official Membership, 11/1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- DC Public Schools Systemwide Training Opportunities, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- DC Street Address Directory, 04/1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Directory of Housing Shelter Programs, 08/1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Draft Final Report of the Special Committee on Race and Ethnicity, 01/1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Dropout and Migration Statistics, 07/1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Five Year Statistical Glance at DC Public Schools 1986-1991, 11/1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Five Year Statistical Glance at DC Public Schools 1987-1992, 12/1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Five Year Statistical Glance at DC Public Schools 1988-1993, 12/1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- From Crisis to Opportunity: Report of the DC Committee on Public Education, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Georgetown Waterfront Area Study, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Graduate Follow-up Report: Class of 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Greater Washington Research Center Recent Work in Review, 01/1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Housing Policies and Programs, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Housing Situation in Metro DC, 06/1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Influences on Curriculum Development in the Public Schools 1804-1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Metropolitan Bulletin, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Moving Forward: A Collaborative Approach to Early Childhood Development in DC, 09/1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Neighborhoods in the Washington Region, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- The Nonprofit Sector: The Heart of Greater Washington, 07/1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Our Children are Still Waiting, 01/1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Our Children Our Future, 06/1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Parents United / Education interviews and meeting notes, 1991-19892 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Poor Cities: An Analysis of Poverty, 03/1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Population Change in Metro Washington, 04/1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Poverty in Washington, 09/1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Private Management in School Reform, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Proposed Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- A Region Divided: State of Growth in Greater DC, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Regulation of Housing in DC, 05/1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Report of the DC Committee on Public Education, 02/1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- School buildings - statistics and closings [1 of 2], 1965-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- School buildings - statistics and closings [2 of 2], 1982-1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Single-parent Families: A First Look Based on 1990 Census Data, 08/1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Spatial Study of the Jewish Community in Southwest DC 1890-1930, 04/1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Statistical View of the Current DC Voter Roll, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Statues of Washington DC, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Survey of Citizens Attitudes toward the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Survey of Hispanic Businesses, 11/1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Toward an Environmental Plan for DC, 07/1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Urban River: A Staff Proposal for Waterfront Development, 12/1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- The Washington Committee: Improving the Retention and Attaction of Business, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Washington DC In Focus: A Profile from Census 2000, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Welcome to our Schools, circa 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Westmoreland Congregational Church: The First 25 Years, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- What's in it for the Kids, 04/1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)